# Zubair Ashfaque

### Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

My journey from working on internet networks to practicing machine learning neural networks is driven by my passion to discover artificial intelligence. Therefore, completed many online certifications in Data Science, Machine Learning and Python. I am confident my experience and expertise will be a perfect fit for your company.



- mianashfaque@gmail.com
- Lahore, Pakistan
- github.com/zubairashfaque

#### +923018480350

in linkedin.com/in/zubair-ashfaque-ab100621

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### System Analyst

Jazz

07/2017 - Present

Lahore

Jazz is a Pakistani mobile network and internet services provider

#### Tasks

- Setting up Multi-Node Hadoop Cluster Hortonworks using Ambari.
- Data Ingestion from multiple sources using Sqoop Scripts. Shell Scripting creating automatized Shell Scripts for Sqoop, Hive, Spark.
- Perform complete database, operating system and application administration, ensuring 100% system availability for Revenue Assurance & Fraud Management platforms.

Contact: Muhammad Faizan Anwar - faizan.anwar@jazz.com.pk

# **Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) Planning**Jazz

01/2017 - 07/2017

Islamabaa

#### Tasks

 Design, implementation, deployment, and maintenance of middleware architecture integrated with CRM (Siebel), Electronic Financial Inventory Control System (EFICS), Billing System (Geneva) and Provisioning System (Comptel).

Contact: Jalal Shahid - jalal.shahid@guest.jazz.com.pk

# **Broadband Supervisor**

PTCL

2009 – 2011 Lahore

PTCL provides telephone and internet services nationwide and is the backbone for the country's telecommunication infrastructure

#### Achievements/Tasks

 Configuring different ADSL routers & modems solving different problems regarding DSL and IPTV. Additional task was to develop and maintain the database of BCMS which was a complaint management system.

# **SKILLS**

Data Science, Machine Learning, Python Programming, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Convolution Neural Network, Artificial Neural Network, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing

Name of the institution that issued/awarded it

### **PROGRAMMING**

Python

PySpark

SQL

TensorFlow

Pytorch

Keras

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

San Francisco Journey planner 🗹

 With help of foursquare data able to recommend places to stay(Hotels), visiting places and best place to eat.

Image Classifier - Cats vs Dogs vs Different species with help Tensorflow 2

 Able to develop a predictive model that can predict different cats and dogs species with accuracy 96 in Tensorflow 2.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor in Telecom Systems**

Beaconhouse National University

2005 - 2009

# **CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES**

Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai | Coursera

IBM AI Engineering by IBM | Coursera

Advanced Data Science with IBM | Coursera

Certified Data Scientist | DataCamp

TensorFlow in Practice by deeplearning.ai | Coursera

## **SOFTWARE**



# MACHINE LEARNING

